txdmv.gov 2017-06-25

# TxDMV.GOV - Privacy Policy

This web site is an official Texas Department of Motor Vehicles (TxDMV) computer system operated for authorized use only and provided as a public service. This policy describes TxDMV's privacy and security practices regarding information collected from visitors to the site, including what information is collected and how that information is used.

Regardless of the information being transmitted to TxDMV, we will protect all such information consistent with applicable law. The privacy of our customers and the security of this site are of utmost importance to TxDMV. This policy applies to all pages beginning with www.txdmv.gov and www.dmv.state.tx.us.

Note: This policy does not apply whenever visitors leave the TxDMV domains and follow a link to another site, including the sites of state agencies and local governments.

**Notice of Monitored Use**

This site is monitored to ensure proper operation, to verify the function of applicable security features and for similar purposes. Unauthorized attempts to upload information, change information on this site, or otherwise cause damage are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under Texas Penal Code Chapters 33 (Computer Crimes) or 33A (Telecommunications Crimes).

#### Information We Collect Automatically

**If you visit a TxDMV site to read or download information:**

  * Your web browser automatically sends us (and we may retain) information such as the: 
    * Internet domain through which you access the Internet;
    * Internet Protocol address of the computer you are using;
    * type of browser software and operating system you are using;
    * date and time you access our site; and
    * Internet address of the site from which you linked directly to our site.
  * We will use this information as aggregate data to help us maintain this site, e.g., to determine the number of visitors to different sections of our site, to ensure the site is working properly, and to help us make our site more accessible and useful.
  * We will not use this information to identify individuals, except for site security or law enforcement purposes.
  * We will not obtain personally-identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information.

#### Other Information We Collect

If you choose to identify yourself (or otherwise provide us with personal information) when you use our online forms:

  * We will collect (and may retain) any personally identifying information, such as your name, street address, email address, and phone number, and any other information you provide. We will use this information to try to fulfill your request and may use it provide you with additional information at a later time. We will not disclose such information to third parties, except as specified in this privacy policy.
  * If you request information, services, or assistance, we may disclose your personal information to those third parties that (in our judgment) are appropriate in order to fulfill your request. If, when you provide us with such information, you specify that you do not want us to disclose the information to third parties, we will honor your request. Note, however, that if you do not provide such information, it may be impossible for us to refer, respond to or fulfill your request.
  * If your communication relates to a law enforcement matter, we may disclose the information to law enforcement agencies that we deem appropriate.

Note: An individual who chooses to submit information in electronic format through this website is entitled, on request, to receive and review the information TxDMV collects about the individual, and to have TxDMV correct the information. Please [contact TxDMV](mailto:webteam@TxDMV.gov) with your request.

#### Cookies

The TxDMV site may use cookies to provide interactive pages, such as web-based forms and surveys. TxDMV does not use cookies for other purposes. These cookies are not required for site functionality. Additionally, third-party widgets such as Google Analytics or YouTube may install cookies depending on their configuration. You are not required to accept any cookies to use this site.

#### Google Analytics

We use the “Google Analytics” tool to collect information about use of the TxDMV site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics in the aggregate and only to improve this site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html) (as [amended for government websites](https://www.archives.gov/files/social-media/terms-of-service/tos-googleanalytics.pdf)) and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html). You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by [disabling cookies](http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml) on your browser.

#### Release of Information

All information collected or maintained by TxDMV is subject to the provisions of the Texas Public Information Act (Chapter 552, Texas Government Code). The identity of most members of the public who communicate with state agencies through the Internet is confidential under Texas law. Exceptions to confidentiality may be reviewed at Texas Government code, Section 552.137.

TxDMV complies with the [State Web Site Link and Privacy Policy](http://publishingext.dir.texas.gov/portal/internal/resources/DocumentLibrary/State%20Website%20Linking%20and%20Privacy%20Policy.pdf). TxDMV encourages organizations that link to this web site to comply with the provisions of the State Web Site Link and Privacy Policy, especially regarding protection of the privacy rights of individuals, and to make reasonable efforts to provide accessible sites.
